The call to “know yourself” has been there since ancient times, but our sense of self doesn’t always match what others perceive.
“认识你自己”的呼声自古就有，但我们的自我认知并不总是和别人看到的一致。
Considering the stories we tell about ourselves can help us to change our minds for better.
审视我们讲述自己的那些故事，可以帮助我们朝更好的方向改变想法。
For many years psychologists saw identity as a combination of someone’s values, beliefs, goals and social roles.
多年来，心理学家把身份认同看作一个人的价值观、信念、目标和社会角色的结合。
Then, in the 1980s, Bob Johnson created the life story model of identity, in which he proposes that, as we go through life, these core features are built in with our memories to create a personal story through which we understand our lives.
后来，在20世纪80年代，鲍勃·约翰逊创立了身份认同的“人生故事”模型。他在该模型中提出，在人生历程中，这些核心特征与我们的记忆融为一体，形成一个个人故事，我们借此理解自己的人生。
Our life story is something that starts coming together in our teenage years, when we begin to organise our lives into chapters around key events or life changes, and begin to see ourselves as both the central character and, to a varying extent, the story’s author.
我们的人生故事从青少年时期开始逐渐成形。那时，我们开始围绕关键事件或人生变化，把生活组织成一个个章节，并开始把自己既看作故事的主角，也在不同程度上看作故事的作者。
People with more consistent stories tend to have a stronger sense of identity, and they feel their life has more meaning, direction and sense of purpose.
故事更连贯的人往往身份感更强，他们觉得自己的人生更有意义、更有方向、更有目标感。
Such people show greater overall life satisfaction, too.
这样的人整体生活满意度也更高。
Johnson has also investigated the link between well-being and certain story themes.
约翰逊还研究了幸福感与某些故事主题之间的联系。
He discovered that whether someone describes having had some control over events in their past is an important predictor of a person’s mental health.
他发现，一个人是否描述自己曾对过去的事情有过一定的掌控，是预测其心理健康状况的重要指标。
Another key theme involves finding some kind of positive meaning after stressful events.
另一个关键主题是在经历压力事件后找到某种积极意义。
“People could talk about gaining knowledge or personal growth,” says Johnson.
“人们可能会谈到收获了知识或个人成长，”约翰逊说。
His research shows that this is often missing for people with mental health conditions.
他的研究表明，有心理健康问题的人往往缺少这一点。
The good news is that there is evidence we can learn to change our own story.
好消息是，有证据表明我们可以学会改变自己的故事。
Lisa Green, another researcher, sounds a few notes of caution.
另一位研究者丽莎·格林提醒人们，有几点需要谨慎。
For instance, hearing about the power of redemptive stories, many people may feel forced to find a positive angle on horrible events.
例如，听说“救赎式”故事的力量后，许多人可能会觉得自己被迫要从可怕的事件中找出积极的一面。
She says that Western culture already pushes people to look for the silver lining behind every cloud.
她说，西方文化本来就在推动人们去寻找每片乌云背后的一线光明。
If you want to turn over a new leaf, though, one top tip is that it helps to choose a significant date that signals the start of a new “chapter”.
不过，如果你想重新开始，有一条绝佳的建议：选一个有意义的日子来标志新“章节”的开始，这会很有帮助。
Contrary to popular doubt, resolutions made on 1 January are more effective for this reason.
与人们普遍的怀疑相反，正因为这个原因，在1月1日立下的决心反而更有效。
So, whether your goal is saving money or getting fit, there is no better time to become the author of our own destiny.
所以，无论你的目标是存钱还是健身，都没有比现在更好的时机来成为自己命运的作者了。